## Ammar Sahyoun

Lund, Skane County, Sweden



ammarzgr@hotmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ammar-sahyoun



0046 739 714925



https://ammarsahyoun.github.io/portfolio/

## Summary

I am a passionate Backend programmer with two years of experience in web development. besides I have got Yrkeshögskoleexamen 2020 along with 4 months intern in the Machine Learning analytics team. Currently, I'm studying IT-Security påbyggnadskurs and actively seeking to use my proven development skills in Python, Java, and SQL.

## **Experience**



#### Al Developer

#### Sogeti

Aug 2020 - Dec 2020 (5 months)

As an Al developer, I learn the GIS techniques that helped me in using the satellite image metadata aiming to prepare a project for the Swedish Agriculture authority, where my contribution was in automating a Python code that download, reprocess and calculate the indicator in Time series analysis to help in crops monitoring.



#### Web Developer

Lyre Co

Apr 2013 - Jun 2015 (2 years 3 months)

Maintain the dynamic website and create new HTML, CSS offers.

Maintain MySQL database, and create new REST API.



#### **Maintenance Technician**

#### Nokia

Mar 2003 - Nov 2011 (8 years 9 months)

I have Performed testing tuning and maintenance of electronic circuit via signal generator, GSM tester, signal analyzer and oscilloscope. I have good experience in electronics soldering, troubleshooting and electronics schematics.

#### **Education**



#### Lexicon Malmö AB

**IT-Security** May 2021 - Sep 2021 **Backend CyberSecurity** 



#### **Komvux Lund**

Grundläggande nivå, Svenska som andra språk Jan 2021 - Jun 2021

## Handelsakademin

Yrkeshögskoleexamen, Object-oriented programming and Al 2019 - 2020

Part of the course was object-oriented programming in (Html, CSS, Javascript), Java and working in practical projects with different relational databases.

The second part of the course deals with AI and data analysis, ML, ANN, TensorFlow, AWS deployment.

## Damascus University

Bachelor, Electronics Engineer - Control 1995 - 1998 Basic electronics PCB design, programming and system control.

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

Mathematics for Machine Learning: Linear Algebra-Imperial College London Coursera Course Certificates
4Y876TBJPZ5L

# IBM Data Science Professional Certificate - IBM Tealeaf A2U24LMGEYKG

- Google cloud Launching into Machine Learning Google Cloud Minnesota Z6KPR7YM2TXD
- GIS Data Formats, Design and Quality University of California, Davis GEQG828NRVVZ

#### Skills

Python • SQL • Java • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Agile Methodologies • Artificial Intelligence (AI) • REST APIs • ArcGIS Products • AWS SageMaker • Microsoft Power BI